LALIT BAR

Software developer with 3+ years experience in Web and iOS development, master's degree in computer science, research experience in applied cryptography; deep sense of design & aesthetics, sincere attention to detail, and demonstrated ability to lead teams and shape products.

+1 415-915-0941

mail@lalit.bar

in linkedin.com/in/lalitbar

EDUCATION

MS, Computer Science California State University 2014 – 2017

BE, Electronics Engineering Nagpur University, India 2009 – 2013

SKILLS

Development

Web: HTML, CSS, JavaScript (ES6–2020), Less, Sass, jQuery, PHP, Laravel, Node.js, Express, SQL, RESTful APIs, PostgreSQL, React, Redux, GraphQL, Jest, Enzyme, Semantic UI, Bootstrap, D3.js, Highcharts, Firebase, Stripe, PWAs

Apple: Swift, SwiftUI, Objective-C, UIKit, AppKit, Xcode, Instruments

Product & Design

Product Strategy & Research, Product Management, Product Marketing, Business Development, UI/UX Design, Interaction Design, Wire-framing, User-flow mapping, Sketch, InVision Studio

Other

C, C++, Git, SVN, Homebrew, Terminal, Vagrant, Docker, NPM, Kubernetes, Agile (Scrum)

EXPERIENCE

INTERNET BRANDS | San Francisco, CA | July 2018 – July 2020 Web Developer

Worked on a number of Internet Brands websites, portals, and internal tools as part of company's front end engineering team.

- Developed complete front-end for Leads Admin (company's leads management platform used to manage & deliver leads to clients).
- Worked extensively on CMS development, including 'Quasar' sitewide theme system for Nolo.com and network websites.
- Wrote & maintained front-end for several most visited page types such as Nolo homepage, lawyer search, results, profile page, article page, homepages of Nolo network sites, and lead generation paths.
- Implemented rich email templates for automated lead and transaction emails for Nolo websites and WebMD.com. Also created seasonal promos for store.nolo.com.
- R&D: Designed and developed data-visualization page templates for Article pages using D3.js and Highcharts/Highmaps.

EVENTMATE, INC. | New York, NY | July 2017 – July 2018 **iOS Developer**

Designed, developed, and managed the product - conception to launch.

- Developed a real-time swipe-and-match engine for event attendees so they can network and communicate before an event.
- Created a custom messaging service using Firebase, the calendar screen, profile page, event filter, and tickets screen.
- Wrote the ticketing [IAP] component of the app for paid events with Stripe integration; added support for Apple Pay.
- Implemented a mining tool to easily import events from Eventbrite.
- Led the product strategy and competition research, rearchitected the product-flow from the ground up, and redesigned the UX.

PROJECTS

Soundboard, In and Out (CSS, Javascript)

A browser-based app which lets you compose music with your keyboard, and a browser-based calculator to record & calculate personal finances.

Security & Privacy in Internet Communication, or lack thereof.

(Applied Cryptography)

Graduate Research Project on the mathematical loopholes of widely used internet communication protocols: SMTP and Axolotl (Signal).

BeerGuts, an iOS app (Objective-C, Xcode, Sketch)

Developed an iOS app called 'BeerGuts' – reviews and ratings system for craft beer by scanning the barcode using iPhone's camera.

Meredith (C, MATLAB, LabVIEW)

Created a software tool to process raw skin imagery using Image Processing algorithms for detection of early stages of Melanoma.